Guide to the North American 19th century theatre broadside collection, 1850-1867
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
North American 19th century theatre broadside collection
1850-1867
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections and Archives.
C0081
2 linear ft.; 1 box
This collection contains around 100 theatre broadsides from the mid-nineteenth century. Nearly all of the broadsides were published in Boston, advertising theatre, opera, and lighter fare in various Boston venues.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in 2008.
Historical Information
Since the eighteenth century, theatre-going in Boston has been quite popular, even if not entirely legal. In the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, Boston was in conflict between a Puritan history and artistic freedom. Theaters often used non-controversial or misleading names (such as the Boston Museum) to partially disguise their identity as a theatre. However, this struggle between religious and artistic ideas lasted into the 20th century.
Theatre in Boston flourished throughout most of the nineteenth century despite this ongoing feud. Smaller playhouses led to more prominent theatres such as the Boston Theatre (1854-1925), Boston Museum (1841-1903), and the Howard Anthenaeum (1845-1953). These major theatres were generally located close to Boston's commercial center and the Beacon Hill residences of affluent theatre attendees.
Scope and Content
This collection contains around 100 theatre broadsides from the mid-nineteenth century. Nearly all of the broadsides were published in Boston, advertising theatre, opera, and lighter fare in various Boston venues. Other locations include venues in New York and Canada. The collection contains an estimated forty broadside bills for performances at the Boston Theatre between 1954-1958, thirty for performances at the Howard Anthenaeum between 1951-1957, twenty at the Boston Museum in 1952-1958, and others at the Boston National Theatre, the Boston Academy of Music, and City Hall.
Most of the broadsides measure approximately 7" x 19", with some variation, and feature classic nineteenth-century typography with artful fonts and little pointing hands. Some of the broadsides are also accompanied by interesting graphics along the margins. The collection includes ads for such varied bills as Adelina Patti in Donizetti's Lucia Di Lammermoor; G.G. Spear in the drama, Moll Pitcher! The Fortune Teller; a Pyne and Harrison Opera Company production of Rip Van Winkle; and a drama by Dion Boucicault and E. H. House titled Arrah-Na-Pogue! Or, the Wicklow Wedding, which advertises segregated seating for blacks and warns that women will not be admitted if unaccompanied by a man.
Arrangement
Organized mainly by venue. Some single broadsides grouped together.
Series 1: National Theatre of Boston, 1850-1857 (Box 1)
Series 2: Boston Museum, 1852-1858 (Box 1)
Series 3: Boston Theatre, 1854-1858 (Box 1)
Series 4: Howard Anthenaeum, 1851-1857 (Box 1)
Series 5: Boston Academy of Music, 1860 (Box 1)
Series 6: Canada and New York City, 1855-1867 (Box 1)
Series 7: Boston and New York City, 1850s-1860s (Box 1)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Boston Museum (1847-1903); Boston Theatre (Washington Street, Boston, Mass.); Howard Athenaeum.
Subjects:
Theatre--Massachusetts--Boston.; Theatre--New York--New York.; Theatre--Canada--New Brunswick.
Document Types:
Broadsides--1850-1870.
Contents List
- Series 1: National Theatre of Boston Broadsides, 1850-1857
  This series contains six broadsides of performances at the National Theatre of Boston, ranging from 6"x15" to 7"x21".
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, October 25, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "Life of a Woman", "Child of the Regiment", Mr. Murdoch performing.
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, March 10, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Governor Boutwell and Lieut. Gov. Cushman visiting theatre, "Henry VIII", farewell engagement of Charlotte Cushman - impersonating Queen Katherine, Mrs. Simpson, and Meg Merriles - "Simpson and Co.", "I've Swallowed a Policeman".
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, February 28, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    French and Spanish Dancers, "Naval Engagements", "The Omnibus", "The Phenomenon in a Smock Frock".
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, January 1, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Mr. James Anderson, Miss Agnes Elsworthy, "Cloud and Sunshine", "Wandering Minstrel".
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, April 28, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "Jack Cade"-or-"The Kentish Rebellion", Mr. Neafie, "Cousin Joe", "THe Corsican Brothers", Judge Conrad.
  - National Theatre of Boston Broadside, March 31 and April 1, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    G.G. Spear's first appearance since returning from California, "Moll Pitcher! The Fortune Teller of Lynn", Dr J.S. Jones, "Paddy the Piper-or-The Cow that Eat him", Miss Ann Bacon.
- Series 2: Boston Museum Broadsides, 1852-1858
  This series contains twenty broadsides of performances at the Boston Museum, ranging from 9"x12" to 7"x20".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, January 24, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mrs. Farren, "Griselda, The Forest Child", "The Milliners' Holiday", "Second Love", Mr. W. Warren.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, January 28, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mrs. Farren, "Second Love", Mrs. H. Eckhardt, "Tit for Tat"-or-"The Double Strategem", J. Palgrave Simpson.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, April 23, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Annual Benefit for Mr. J.H. Angier - treasurer of the museum, "Paul Pry"-or-"I Hope I Don't Intrude", John poole, Esq., "Married Rake", "Two Bonnycastles", "Valentine and Orson".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, October 23, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Benefit of W.H. Smith, "The Cure for the Heart Ache", "Therese"-or-"The Orphan of Geneva"
  - Boston Museum Broadside, December 24, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Last week of Chinese Pagent, "Aladdin"-or-"The Wonderful Lamp", "My Husband's Mirror".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, September, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Miss Julia Bennett, "The Mysterious Stranger", Mr. Warren, The Polka Quadrille, "No Song, No Supper", Gretna Green, Grimshaw, Bagshaw, and Bradshaw.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, September, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Miss Julia Bennett, "Belle's Strategem", Mr. Warren, "Allow me to Apologize", "Farmer's Story", "Make Your Wills".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, October 17, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Farewell Benefit of Mr. J.W. Wallack Jr., Me. Henry Wallack, "Werner"-or-"The Inheritance", "Country Squire"-or-"Two Days at the Hall", "The Fairy Star", Miss Agnes Robertson.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, January 16, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Benefit of Mr. W.H. Smith, Mrs. Annie Senter, Mr. J.W. Wallack, Jr., "Lady of Lyons"-or-"Love and Pride", "How Stout You're Getting".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, November 28, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Valentine and Orson", "Fire Eater".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, August 27, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Declaring theatre's thirteenth season as individual enterprise amusement for the general public without the "influence of a host of stockholders", Mrs. Farren, "Venice Preserved", "The Dead Shot", Thomas otway, "School for Scandal".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, April 8, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Aladdin"-or-"The Wonderful Lamp", Mr. W.H. Smith
  - Boston Museum Broadside, April 13, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Benefit of Mrs. Annie Senter, "The Hunchback", James Sheridan Knowles, "Like as Two Peas", Miss A. Raymond, Mr. S. Lake, "Uncle Tom's Cabin".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, May 16, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Benefit of Mr. J. Proctor, Mrs. J. Proctor, "Nick of the Woods"-or-"The Jibbenainosay", "Dumb Belle", "Loan of a Lover", Mr. James Bennett.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, September 21, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Image of the museum, declaring the theatre's thirteenth season, farewell benefit for Mrs. Ferren, "Loving Woman", "Captive"-or-"Scenes in a Madhouse", "The Daughter of the Regiment"-or-"The Gallant 21st", Mark Lemon, Esq., Mrs. Charles Howard,
  - Boston Museum Broadside, September 8, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Image of museum, declaration of 13th season, Mrs. Farren, "The Love Chase", James Sheridan Knowles, "Perfection"-or-"The Maid of Munster", "The Loving Woman".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, November 24, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Thanksgiving Day, "Talisman"-or-" The Fairy's Favor".
  - Boston Museum Broadside, February 28, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "The Magic Mirror"-or-"The Spirit of the Age", H.J. Conway, Esq.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, April 27, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Farewell benefit of Mrs. Annie Senter, "The Wife"-or-"A Tale of Mantua", "Day After the Wedding", Mrs. Charles Kemble, "The Mysterious Stranger", a new petit comedy in rehearsal from London.
  - Boston Museum Broadside, February 8, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Farewell benefit of Miss Fanny Vining and E.L. Davenport, "Charity's Love"-or-"The Trials of a Heart", "Morning Call", "Faint Heart Never Won Fair Lady", Benefit of Mr. J.H. Ring, Jefferson S. Batkins, "The Silver Spoon, Mrs. H. Eckhardt, Miss A. Raymond, Mr. S. Lake.
- Series 3: Boston Theatre, 1854-1858
  This series contains thirty-six broadsides of performances at the Boston Theatre, ranging from 7"x18" to 6"x24".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, May 3, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mrs. C.N. Sinclair, Mrs. Forrest, "Ingomar! The Barbarian", Mr. George Vandenhoff, "The Swiss Swains", present demands against firm of WRIGHT, FENNO, and BIRD for liquidation, J.B. Wright, Ms. A. Raymond, Mr. S. Lake.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, March 10, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Mrs. Barrow, "Olympia"-or-"The Life of an Actress", poem of "Hiawatha", Mr. T. Comer, "Mr. and Mrs. Lilly W.", orchestral performance, notice of a box in second tier assigned for the use of colored persons.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, October 20, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Miss Julia Dean, "Evadne"-or-"The Statue", "Honey Moon", orchestral performance, Mr. T. Comer.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, April 5, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Invisible Prince"-or-"The Island of Tranquil Delights" - produced at cost of several thousand dollars, "Priestess".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, April 28, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Shakespearean Pagent, "Midsummer Night's Dream", "Pyramus and Thisbe".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, April 17, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Great fairy opera produced at cost of several thousand dollars - "Cinderella" - full New York chorus joined to the Boston choristers, T. Comer, H.W. Du Lang, Miss Louisa Pyne, Mr. W. Harrison, Mr. John Wood, W.H. Smith.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, March 24, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mrs. Hudson Kirby, Mr. James Bennett, "The Wife", "Young Widow"-or-" A Lesson for Lovers", notice for a box for colored persons.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, November 12, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mr. Forrest, "Macbeth", orchestral performance, "Pleasant Neighbor", beware of sparious tickets offered for sale in streets.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, March 16, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Mr. and Mrs. John Gilbert, "Town and Country", "Jenny Lind", "Uncle John", Mrs. Julia Hayne/Miss Julia Dean.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, January 10, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    The WOnderful Ravels, Mlle. Robert from the Academy of Paris, M. Leon Espinoza, "School Master", "Festival Dansant", "Jocko-The Brazilian Ape", "La Esmerelda", corps de ballet.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 22, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Merchant of Venice", "Sophia's Supper", orchestral performances, Wanted: 100 auxiliares for "Richard III".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, June 3, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Miss Charlotte Cushman as "Meg Merrilies", Mr. E.L. Davenport, "Guy Mannering"-or-"The Gipsey's Prophecy", box reserved for colored persons on second tier.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, June 11, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Farewell benefit for Mrs. Barrow, Miss Rosa Bennett from Haymarket Theatre in London and Wallack's in New York, "Mysterious Stranger", "London Assurance".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, April 2, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Farewell benefit of Edwin Booth, "The Robbers of the Black Forest of Bohemia", orchestral piece, "Katharine and Petruchio"-or-"The Taming of the Shrew", "Jessie Brown"-or-"The Relief of Lucknow", Agnes RObertson, Dion Bourcicault, notice of seating for colored persons.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, January 5, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Matilda Herron, H.F. Daly, notice of seating for colored persons, "Camille" - translated from French, orchestral performance, "Wanted, 1000 Milliners for the Gold Diggings!".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 11, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Mr. Charles Thorne, Mrs. Charles Thorne, notice of seating for colored persons, "The Stranger"-or-"Misanthropy and Repentance", "The Avenger"-or-"The Moor of Sicily".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, November 19, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Bonzani Ballet Troupe, Cesare Cecchetti, notice of seating for colored persons, "Faust", "Biricchino Di. Parici (Le Gamin De. Paris)", "The Secret", The Ronzani Ballet Troupe, "Golden Horse".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 25, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Richard III"-or the-"Battle of Bosworth Field", "Milliners' Holiday"-or-"Girls on a Frolic", "Money".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, March 12, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Mr. G. Pauncefort, "King John", "Used Up!", Invisible Prince", "The Priestess".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, April 13, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Benefit of Mr. Barry, "Rule a Wife and Have a Wife", "King and the Mimic", "Norma Trauestie" from Adelphi Theatre in London, theatre closed one night for "Cinderella" rehearsal.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, January 30, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mr. Hackett, Senorita Soto, Madame Ciocca, G.W. SMith, Mr. and Mrs. John Wood, a grand ballet divertisment, "King Henry IV", "Loan of a Lover", opera of "Lucrezia Borgia".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, October 16, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Miss Julia Dean, "Love", James Sheridan Knowles, orchestral performance, "New Footman", "The Hunchback", "Romeo and Juliet".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, September 24, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Two copies of this broadside.
    Notice of seating for colored persons, "Retribution" from London, "Exhibition Song of All Nations" - sung by Mrs. John Wood during the Great Exhibition in London, "Mischief Making", "Tempest", ticket holder will be accepted any night due to a severe storm.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 18, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Merry Wives of Windsor"-or-"Falstaff in Love", orchestral performance, "Sophia's Supper", "Richard III", "School for Scandal".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 13, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Beggar's Opera" - with songs, ballads, and duets - "Postilion Polka", "Pleasant Neighbor", "Bohemian Girl", "La Sonnambula", Books for opera on sale at theatre.
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, November 15, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mr. Forrest, "Othello - The Moor of Venice", orchestral performance, "New Footman".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, June 7, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Ravel Troupe, Francois Ravel, Yrca Mathias, "Le Exercises de Corde", "Le Diable Amoureaux", "The Green Monster".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 27, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notice of seating for colored persons, "Temprest"-or-"The Enchanted Island".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, September 25, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mr. G. Vandenhoff from Europe, "Money", orchestral performance, "Betty Martin", "School for Scandal", "The Laughing Hyena".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, September 18, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Much Ado About Nothing", orchestral performance, "Game of Romps", "A Cure for the Heartache", "12th Night".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 3, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Miss Adelaide Phillipps, "Devil's Bridge" opera, song list from opera, "Sketches in India", "The Duenna", "The Laughing Hyerna".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, December 4, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Miss Adelaide Phillipps, "Duenna" opera, song list from opera, "Laughing Hyena".
  - Boston Theatre Broadside, November 21, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mr. Forrest, "Gladiator", orchestral performance, "Swiss Cottage"-or-"Why Don't She Marry?", "Metamora! Metamora".
- Series 4: Howard Anthenaeum, 1851-1857
  This series contains nineteen broadsides of performances at the Howard Anthenauem in Boston, ranging from 7"x12 1/2" to 7 1/2"x20".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, January 23, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    colored persons admitted to third circle only, auction for choice seats, Clark and Hatch auctioneers, "The Black Domino", Benefit of Mad. Anna Thillon, Miss Julia Daly, J.M. White, "The Little Treasure", "Married Rake", "Day After the Wedding", omnibus transport options.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, December 14, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "Still Waters Run Deep", "The Little Treasure", Miss Louisa Howard, Miss Charlotte Crampton, Mr. Henry Ferren, "Belphegor the Mountebank", colored persons admitted to the gallery only.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, December 9, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    colored persons admitted to third circle only, Mrs. Warner, "Love" with full orchestra, Sheridan Knowles, Mr. W. Marshall, "French Spy", "Anne Blake" from London, omnibus transport options.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, December 12, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Benefit for Mrs. Hamblin, Mrs. Shaw, Sheridan Knowles, "Love", Mr. A.W. Fenno, Mr. John Gilbert, Miss Lucille Western, "Honesty the Best Policy", "Love Chase", "Douglas", Mr. W. Marshall, comic vocalist Mr. Pete Morns, colored persons admitted to upper tier only.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, December 8, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to third circle only, Mrs. Warner, "Winter's Tale", "Katharine and Petruchio" - chorus line written for spectators to imagine a lapse of sixteen years, "Ingomar".
    On reverse of broadside: "Opinions of the English Press of the celebrated tragic actress Mrs. Warner".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, February 3, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to third circle only, farewell engagement of Mr. Buchanan, "Hamlet! Prince of Denmark", orchestral performance, "Artful Dodger", "Black Domino", "Daughter of the Regiment", "Crown Diamonds", Madame Anna Thillon, "King Lear", "A New Way to Pay Old Debts", omnibus transport options.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, October 24, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Pyne and Harrison English Opera Troupe, Benefit of Mr. W. Harrison, Miss Louisa pyne singing "The Skylark" and "Rode's Celebrated Air and Variations", Mr. W. Harrison singing "Oh! Whisper What thou Feelist!", "Crown Diamonds", "Contentment Versus Riches", "The Beggar's Opera", colored persons admitted to the gallery only.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, May 7, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    colored persons admitted to gallery only, farewell benefit of Mr. and Mrs. Charles Matthews, "Handsome Husband", "Married for Money", "The Honeymoon", "Turning the Tables", "The Comical Countess", "The Gun Trick", "He Would be an Actor", benefit of Mr. John E. Owens.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, November 23, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Mr. Wallack, "Don Caesar De Bazan", Miss Fanny Howard, orchestral performance, "Old Oak Chest"-or-"The Smuggler's Son and the Robber's Daughter", Wanted: ladies for the Corps de Ballet.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, October 1, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    J.M. Field and T. Placide - Managers, "Still Waters Run Deep", Mr. J.S. Browne, "Sketches in India".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, April 10, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only, Miss Kimberly, "Hamlet", Mr. McDonough, "Robert Macaire", Benefit of Mrs. I.C. Frost, "Clara"-or-"The Christian Heroine".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, August 21, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only - no free list, coolest theatre in the city!, Mr. W.R. Blake, Mr. George Jordan, "Old Heads and Young Hearts", Miss Charlotte Thompson, Mrs. Hudson Kirby, "Speed the Plough", "The School for Scandal".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, December 25, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "Little Treasure", "Wandering Minstrel", "Antony and Cleopatra", Miss H. Lang, "Serious Family", "Strong Minded Woman", "Two Lovers and a Life", "he Sea of Ice"-or-"The Wild Flowers of Mexico" - playing at all theatres in London.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, September 22, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Theatre re-opened for a short season before managers return south, Mr. J.S. Brown, "My Aunt", "My Young Wife", Old Umbrella", "Artful Dodger".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, July 17, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only - no free list, coolest theatre in the city, Mrs. Barrow, "London Assurance", "Pleasant Neighbors", "Po-Ca-Hon-Tas" under direction of author Mr. John Brougham.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, July 22, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only - no free list, Mr. John Brougham, Mr. and Mrs. E.L. Davenport, "Po-Ca-Hon-Tas" - music re-set by James G. Meader, instrumentalist Mr. John Holloway, "Bachelor of Arts", "Dombey and Son".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, February 3, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Heron Children, "A Kiss on the Neck"-or-"Can Borders have Pie for Luncheon", programme of scenery, "Irish Lion", "Waterman", Miss Mary Ann Heron, Miss Fanny Herron, "Richard the Third", children under 12 admitted half price.
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, April 9, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only, "Delicate Ground", Mrs. Barrow, Jacob Barrow, Henry Wallack, orchestral performance, John Holloway, "Honey Moon", "School for Scandal", "The Rivals", "Beatrice".
  - Howard Anthenaeum Broadside, January 20, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Colored persons admitted to gallery only, Benefit for Mr. James Anderson, "Civilization", John Wilkins, Esq., "Elder Brother", Miss Fanny Morant, orchestral performance, Miss Davenport, G.K. Dickinson, "Hotel Charges", Notice: $25 reward for information about people throwing articles from gallery of theatre.
- Series 5: Boston Academy of Music, 1860
  This series contains one broadside of performances at the Boston Academy of Music, 5 3/4"x11 3/4".
  - Boston Academy of Music Broadside, January 3, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Italian opera "Emani", Sig. Muzio, new chandelier - largest in US or Europe - manufactured by Cornelius and Baker of Philadelphia, N.W. Turner and Co., Ms. Adelina Patti, "Lucia Di Lammermoor", grand orchestra and chorus, opera sheet music available for 25 cents, Sig. Amati Dubreul, Mme. Pauline Colson.
- Series 6: Canada and New York City, 1855-1867
  This series contains six broadsides of performances at St John's Dramatic Lyceum in Canada, Mechanic's Institute in New York, Wallack's Theatre in New York, Metropolitan Theatre in New York, Burton's in New York, and Lorimier Hall. Size of broadsides range from 7 1/2"x16 1/2" to 6 1/2"x22 1/2".
  - St John's Dramatic Lyceum Broadside (New Brunswick, Canada), July 26, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    J.W. Longeran, "Arrah-na-Pogue"-or-"The Wiclow Wedding", Mr. Frank Roche, Shirley France, Miss Kennedy, the two back seats of the Dress Cirle are set apart for the exclusive use of colored people, ladies unaccompanied by gentlemen not admitted.
  - Mechanic's Institute Broadside (New York), July 24, 26, 29, 1850s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Three Nichts in Scotland, Mr. Kennedy - Scottish vocalist coming from performances in London, songs of Scotland, bagpipes, "A crack wi' Jamie Hogg and Christopher North", Ms. Kennedy.